<dashboard stylesheet="application.css">
	<label>Splunk App for Cisco ISE Configuration</label>

	<row>
		<html>
<h2>Steps to Setup the Splunk App for Cisco Identity Services Engine</h2>
<p><strong>Important note:</strong> This app is only contains dashboards and reports.  No data is collected by this app.  For Cisco ISE data collection, install and configure the separate <a href="https://apps.splunk.com/app/1915/">Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE</a></p>

<h1>Overview</h1>

<p>Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE) is a security policy management and control platform. It automates and simplifies access control and security compliance for wired, wireless, and VPN connectivity.</p>

<p>The Splunk App for Cisco ISE includes sample dashboards and reports for profiling, authentication, system statistics, alarms, and location awareness.  A separate <a href="https://apps.splunk.com/app/1915/">Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE</a> needs to be installed to collect data from Cisco ISE systems.</p>

<h2>Release Notes</h2>

<p>This version of the Splunk App for Cisco ISE only contains dashboards and reports.  No data collection is performed.  In order to collect data from a Cisco ISE system, install the separate <a href="https://apps.splunk.com/app/1915/">Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE</a>.</p>

<h3>Support and resource links</h3>

<p><strong>This is a community-supported app.</strong></p>

<p>Access questions and answers at <a href="http://answers.splunk.com/app/questions/1589.html">answers.splunk.com/app/questions/1589.html</a></p>

<p>For general Splunk Enterprise support, see the Splunk Support Programs page:
<a href="http://www.splunk.com/support">www.splunk.com/support</a></p>

<p>If you have specific questions about the separate Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE, log a case using the Splunk Support Portal at <a href="https://www.splunk.com/index.php/submit_issue">www.splunk.com/index.php/submit_issue</a></p>

<h1>Installation and Configuration</h1>

<h2>Hardware and software requirements</h2>

<h3>Prerequisites</h3>

<p>Install and configure the <a href="https://apps.splunk.com/app/1915/">Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE</a>.</p>

<h3>Splunk Enterprise system requirements</h3>

<p>Because this add-on runs on Splunk Enterprise, all of the Splunk Enterprise system requirements apply.</p>

<h2>Installation Steps</h2>

<ol>
<li>Download and install the Splunk Add-on for Cisco ISE (https://apps.splunk.com/app/1915/).</li>
<li>Delete any previous version of the Splunk for Cisco ISE application.</li>
<li>Download the Splunk App for Cisco ISE https://apps.splunk.com/app/1589/</li>
<li>From the Splunk Web interface, click on Apps > Manage Apps to open the Apps Management page.</li>
<li>Click Install app from file, locate the downloaded file, and click Upload.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Note</strong>: ensure the “Upgrade app” checkbox is checked.</p>

		</html>
	</row>
</dashboard>
